texthelp.com 2019-04-05

# Texthelp Privacy Policy | Texthelp

## Website privacy policy 

At Texthelp we’re firmly committed to Internet privacy.

This privacy statement discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for all non-excluded websites owned and operated by Texthelp. 

For more information on our Information Security Policy and Texthelp Products Privacy Policy relating to our products that are GDPR, COPPA and FERPA compliant please visit Information Security Policy and Texthelp Products Privacy Policy. 

### Environment variables

We may record your environment variables, such as your IP address, host name, browser type, operating system, etc., to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. This information may be used to help identify you and your shopping cart, track referrals, prevent or report incidents of credit card fraud, or for other purposes deemed reasonable and necessary. 

### Cookies

Our sites may use cookies to keep track of your shopping cart, to personalise our web sites to suit your tastes, to track referral information, and for other purposes. 

### Registration and order forms

Site registration and/or order forms may require users to give us contact information (like their name and email address). We use customer contact information from the registration form to send the user information about our company and to fulfill delivery of ordered products and services. The customer contact information is also used to contact the visitor when necessary. 

Potentially sensitive information (e.g., credit card numbers) is collected through secure server connections.

Non sensitive information may be e-mailed to Texthelp representatives or agents. This e-mail is generally not encrypted. As such, there is a remote possibility that the information could be intercepted by third parties. Visitors always have the option to provide this information in an alternative format. 

### Third party access to information

Only such information as is necessary in order to process payments, and to fulfill product and service delivery requirements will be provided to third-parties. 

Texthelp will comply with any subpoena or summons issued by any federal, state, or local law enforcement or judicial agencies for information. We may voluntarily provide unsolicited information to appropriate authorities if we believe the information is relevant to a criminal investigation. Unless clearly and specifically stated at the point the information is gathered, we will not sell, give away, or otherwise share information about you for any purpose other than the purposes mentioned in this document.

Our websites may contains links to other, non-Texthelp sites. Texthelp Limited is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. 

### Public forums

Our sites may make chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. 

### Security

Our sites have security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. These measures include the use of secure servers to collect the information, encrypted databases, storage of the information in non-public areas of the servers, and other measures as deemed reasonable and necessary. 

### What personal information about customers does Texthelp gather?

We may collect the following information: 

  * name and job title
  * contact information including email address
  * demographic information such as postcode, preferences and interests
  * other information relevant to customer surveys and/or offers

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons: 

  * Internal record keeping
  * We may use the information to improve our products and services
  * We may periodically send promotional communications about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the details which you have provided (you will only be contacted if you have not opted out)
  * From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email, phone, fax or mail. We may use the information to customise the website according to your interests

Texthelp does not share this information with any Third Party. The only exception to this would be a company acting on our behalf for mailing purposes only. We only work with mailing companies who meet our own strict information security policies. 

### Supplementation information

Our sites may supplement the information that you provide with information that is received from third parties. 

### Choice/opt-out

Our sites give users the following options for removing their information from our database to not receive future communications or to no longer receive our service.

You can send email to [info@texthelp.com](mailto:info@texthelp.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy). You can send postal mail to the address which appears at the end of this document.

You can call us at the phone number which appears at the end of this document. 

### Correct/update information

Our sites give users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided.

Email: [info@texthelp.com](mailto:info@texthelp.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy)

Send postal mail to the address which appears at the end of this document.

Call us at the phone number which appears at the end of this page. 

### Links to other websites

This website may contain links to other external sites. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question. 

### Contacting us

Please contact us with any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of our sites, or your dealings with any of our web sites:

Texthelp Ltd  
Lucas Exchange  
1 Orchard Way  
Greystone Road  
Antrim  
Northern Ireland  
BT41 2RU  
Tel: +44(0)28 9442 8105  
Email: [info@texthelp.com](mailto:info@texthelp.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy)
